Guide to the Consumer Reports. Sybil Shainwald papers RL.11855
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Sybil Shainwald papers
1929-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11855
0.6 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Sybil Shainwald is an educator and lawyer who founded and then served as the Director of the Center for the Study of the Consumer Movement at Consumers Union from 1972-1978. The Sybil Shainwald papers include correspondence, clippings, articles, advocacy reports, administrative files, program brochures and other materials. Topics represented include women's health; the establishment of centers for the study of consumer advocates; and history of the consumer movement. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Sybil Shainwald is an educator and lawyer who founded and then served as the Director of the Center for the Study of the Consumer Movement at Consumers Union from 1972-1978. Shainwald was born in 1928 in New York. She attended William and Mary College (BA History, 1948) and worked in New York as a teacher and Title I Reading Program administrator from 1954-1968. Shainwald returned to graduate school at Columbia University (Masters in Political Science, 1972) and later received a law degree from the New York Law School. During that time Shainwald joined Consumers Union and helped to secure NEH grant funding to establish the Center for the Study of the Consumer Movement which she directed until 1978, when she left Consumers Union to go into legal practice.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Sybil Shainwald papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Colton E. Warne papers
Consumer Reports. Consumers Union Foundation records
Collection Overview
The Sybil Shainwald papers include correspondence, clippings, articles, advocacy reports, administrative files, program brochures and other materials. Topics represented include women's health; the establishment of centers for the study of consumer advocates; and history of the consumer movement.
Consumer education; Consumer advocacy; Consumers -- United States; Shainwald, Sybil; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Consumers Union Foundation. Center for the Study of the Consumer Movement
- A National Health System Is a Woman's Issue (National Women's Health Network), 1988 (Box 1)
- A Proposal for the Preservation of Records on Women in the Consumer Movement, 1978 (Box 1)
- Awards, 2007-2010 (Box 1)
- Center for the Study of the Consumer Movement, 1978 (Box 1)
- Clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Colston Warne articles, 1929-1970 (Box 1)
- Consumer standards, 1963-1967 (Box 1)
- Consumers Union historical materials, 1953-2011 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1956-2012 (Box 1)
- Drafts and notes, 1970 (Box 1)
- Drafts and notes, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
- Genesis and Growth of the First Consumer Testing Organization (Master's thesis), 1971; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Guide to Documents of the Consumer Movement, 1980 (Box 1)
- Norman Katz articles, 1973 (Box 1)
- Role of a Board of Directors, 1979 (Box 1)
- Ron Grele interview, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
- Sidney Shainwald Public Interest Lecture programs, 2007-2012 (Box 1)
- Sidney Shainwald tribute to Colston Warne, 1980 (Box 1)